Richard Hendriks

richard.hendriks@piedpiper.com | (912) 555-4321 | Palo Alto, US | piedpiper.com

Summary

Richard hails from **Tulsa**. He has earned degrees from the University of Oklahoma and Stanford. (Go Sooners and Cardinals!) Before starting Pied Piper, he worked for Hooli as a part time software developer. While his work focuses on applied information theory, mostly optimizing lossless compression schema of both the length-limited and adaptive variants, his non-work interests range widely, everything from quantum computing to chaos theory. He could tell you about it, but THAT would NOT be a "length-limited" conversation!

Skills

• Web Development: HTML, CSS, Javascript

• Compression: Mpeg, MP4, GIF

Work Experience

Pied Piper Apr 2014 — Present

CEO/President

- · Build an algorithm for artist to detect if their music was violating copy right infringement laws
- Successfully won Techcrunch Disrupt
- Optimized an algorithm that holds the current world record for Weisman Scores

Hooli Jan 2014 — Apr 2014

Senior Software Engineer

• Worked on optimizing the backend algorithms for Hooli

Software Engineer Jan 2013 — Jan 2014

• Contributed bugfixes and smaller features for Hooli

Volunteering

CoderDojo Jan 2012 — Jan 2013

Teacher

Global movement of free coding clubs for young people.

Awarded 'Teacher of the Month'

Education

Stanford Jun 2011 — Jan 2014

B.S

- DB1101 Basic SQL
- CS2011 Java Introduction

Awards & Recognitions

• **Digital Compression Pioneer Award**: There is no spoon.